A Guide to the Records of the Office of the President, Walter S. Newman, 1947-1962 (Bulk 1947-1961)
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
- Series I. General Correspondence, 1947-1961
  - General Correspondence, 1959
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Steel Scholarship, 1957-1958, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Veterinary Science, Dr. D.F. Watson, Head (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Board (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1960
    - Virginia Agricultural Conference Board (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station (VAES) (Box 18, Folder 8-10)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Educational Foundation, Dr. J.R. Hutcheson, President (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
    - Virginia Tech Athletic Association, F.O. Moseley, Director (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Truck Experiment Station (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Whittemore, Dr. J.W. (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - YMCA (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Accrediting (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Admissions (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Aeronautical Engineering Department (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Agricultural Director of Instruction (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Agricultural Economics (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Agricultural Education (Vocational Education and Business Education) (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Alpha Phi Omega (Social Service) Survey (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Alumni Citations (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Alumni Association, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 26-28)
    - Alumni Association, Fund Council (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Alumni Association, General (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - American Association of University Women (barred from using University facilities after group was integrated) (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Animal Husbandry Department (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Architecture Department (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Athletic Association, F.O. Moseley (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Attorney General A.S. Harrison (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Auditor (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Biology Department (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Biology and Nutrition Department (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Budget, Director of, L.M. Kuhn (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Budget Matters (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Burrus, J.A., Portrait (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Business Administration Department, H.H. Mitchell (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Business Manager, S.K. Cassell (Box 18, Folder 43-44)
    - Centennial Committee (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Chemistry Department, Dr. R.C. Krug (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Civil Engineering Department, Dr. H.M. Morris (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Civil War Commission (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Commandant of Cadets J.M. Devine (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Commencement Exercises (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Commencement Exercises, Requests to be Excused (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Community Concert Association (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Continuing Education (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - CORPS (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Daughtrey, Mr. W.H., Associate Director of Extension (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Development Program (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
    - Dietrick, Dean L.B., Agriculture (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
    - Educational Foundation, Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Electric Power (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - English and Foreign Languages (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Engineering Mechanics (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Enrollment Statistics (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Extension Branches (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Faculty Committees (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Forestry and Conservation (Box 19, Folder 21-22)
    - Fraternities (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Geological Sciences Department (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Governor of Virginia, J. Lindsay Almond (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Guidance and Placement (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Homecoming Committee (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Home Economics Department (Box 19, Folder 29-30)
    - Horticulture Department, Dr. W. Judkins (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Industrial Engineering (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Infirmary, Dr. E.R. Irvin (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Institutional Research, Joint (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Johnston, G. Burke, Dean (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Land-Grant Colleges and Universities (Box 19, Folder 38-39)
    - Legislation (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Library (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Military Department, Colonel E.H. Thompson, Army; Colonel Ray W. Koontz, Air Force (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Pardue, Dr. Louis A., Vice-President and Director of Graduate Studies (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Personnel, Director of, J.W. Garber (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Physics Department (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Planning Engineer, Mr. H.P.C. Vandenburg (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - President's Council (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Publicity, Director of, R.H. M Neil (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Radford College (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Salary Information (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Religious Activities, P.N. Derring, Director (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Religious Life Advisory Committee, Interviews with Ministers (H.W. Sanders) concerning use of War Memorial Chapel (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Salary Schedules (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Scholarships, Fellowships, and Loans (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Southern Regional Educational Board (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
    - State Board of Education (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - State Council of Higher Education, Dr. W.W. McFarland, Director (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Statistics Department (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Student Organizations (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Technical Institutes and Junior Colleges (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Tenure to Engineering Faculty (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Virginia Truck Experiment Station (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Whittemore, Dean J.W., Engineering and Architecture (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - YMCA, Mr. A.L. Payne, Secretary (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, 1961
    - Academic Council (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Admissions, Dr. Dr. P.H. Farrier, Director (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Alumni Association, Fund Council (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Alumni Association, General (Box 20, Folder 32-34)
    - Alumni Citations (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - American Council on Education (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Architecture Department, Professor L.J. Currie, Head (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Association of American Colleges (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Athletic Association, Virginia Tech; Mr. F.O. Moseley, Director (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Attorney General, The Honorable A.S. Harrison (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Auditor, S.G. Cregger (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Biology and Nutrition Department, Dr. R.W. Engel, Head (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Budget, Director of, Mr. L.M. Kuhn (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Budget Matters (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Business Administration Department, Dr. H.H. Mitchell, Head (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Business Manager, S.K. Cassell (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Centennial Committee (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Centennial Info (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Centennial Letters (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Chemical Engineering Department, Dr. F.W. Bull, Head (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Chemistry Department, Dr. R.C. Krug, Head (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Civil War Commission (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - College Calendar (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Commandant of Cadets, General J.M. Devine (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Commandant of Cadets, General Schewe (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Commencement Exercises (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Commencement Exercises, Requests to be Excused (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Community Colleges, Clifton Forge, Covington, Danville; Dr. Stuart B. Row, Coordinator of Branch Institutions (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Community Colleges, Miscellaneous Policies (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Consultative Work for Faculty (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Development Program (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Development Program, Mr. Earl Fisher (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Educational Foundation, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Dr. J.R. Hutcheson, President (Box 21, Folder 22-23)
    - Enrollment Statistics (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Faculty Committees (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Galax, Carroll, Grayson Proposed Community College (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Governor of Virginia, J. Lindsay Almond (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Hahn, Dr. (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Homecoming Committee (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Johnston, Dean G. Burke, Dean, Academic Science and Business Administration (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities, Association of (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities, Centennial (Box 21, Folder 33-34)
    - Legislation (Box 21, Folder 35-37)
    - Library, Mr. Seymour Robb, Librarian (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Naming Buildings, Committee on (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Personnel, Director of; Mr. J.W. Garber, in Richmond (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Radford College, Dr. C.K. Martin, President (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Religious Activities, Dr. P.N. Derring, Director (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke Technical Institute, Dedicated October 20 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
    - Salary Information (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Scholarships, Fellowships, and Loans (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Commission on Colleges and Universities (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Southern Athletic Conference (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - State Board of Education (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - State Council of Higher Education (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Student Letters, Parents and Friends (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Student Organizations (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Dr. H.N. Young and Dr. W.B. Bell (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Truck Experiment Station (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - West, Jas. L.W., Jr., Executive Secretary to President (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Whittemore, Dean J.W., Engineering and Architecture (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - YMCA, Mr. A.L. Payne, Secretary (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Series II. Honorary Awards Committee, 1962
  - Honorary Awards Committee (Box 22, Folder 24)
- Series III. Newman Library Building Project, 1949-1957
  - Library Building, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Library Building, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
  - Library Building, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Library Building, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Library Building, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Library Building, Bids for Excavation (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Library, Color Schedule, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Library Dedication, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Library Furnishings and Equipment, 1954-1958 (Box 23, Folder 10-14)
  - Library Project, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 15-16)
  - Library Project, Outside Utilities Distribution (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Library Survey, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Robb Seymour, Librarian, 1949-1956 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Library Bids, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 20-21)
  - Library Furnishings and Equipment, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 22-23)
- Series IV. Faculty Personnel Cases, 1953-1962
  Scope and Content
  Please note: This series is restricted for 75 years from date of creation. Please contact Special Collections and University Archives for more information.
  - Biology, 1961-1962 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Civil Engineering (Box 24, Folder 3-5)
- Series V. Oversize Materials, 1947-1962
  - Inauguration, 1949 (Folder 1)
  - From General Correspondence (Folder 2)
    - Appalachian Electric Power Company, Claytor Development, map of land to be conveyed to Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1947 (Folder 2)
    - Budget Statements, 1947 (Folder 2)
    - Proposed Controlled Environment Research Laboratory, Virginia Agricultural Extension Service, Map and Architectural Drawings, 1959 (Folder 2)
    - Organizational Chart, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1947 (Folder 2)
    - Organizational Chart, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1962 (Folder 2)
  - From Newman Library Building Project (Folder 2)
    - Architectural drawings of microfilm storage cases, map cases, and enlarging work table, Library Building Project, submitted by Carneal and Johnston, 1954 (Folder 2)
    - Architectural drawing of steel bookstacks, Library Building Project (Folder 2)
      - Carneal and Johnston, 1955 (Folder 2)
      - Preliminary Equipment Layout, Prepared by Library Building Consultants, 1952 (Folder 2)
      - Schedule of Interior Finish, Library for Virginia Tech, 1952 (Folder 2)